Hello friends, my name is Sachin and
today I have brought a new topic for you
which is day care treatment. So
friends, first of all we should know
what is day treatment, any such
disease which can be treated within 24 hours
in a hospital or a day care center
and you go in the morning and
come back to your home in the evening or you stay for four to five hours and are
discharged from there, so
this treatment is called
day care treatment, as the name itself suggests, the treatment is done within the same day
and you
come back from the hospital, so
all these charges of day care are
covered by insurance companies, but there are
some conditions also and see,
mostly surgery is done in the treatment
which is covered, so now let us
understand it a little more that this is
completely different from other treatments, that
if we go to the OPD and we
take some treatment from the doctor in the OPD,
we consult the doctor and we come back, then this is not an
aircraft, we do not consider it as treatment in day care.  It will be done
and at the same time you will not get any claim on the skin, so
we have to understand both the things,
day care treatment is different, orchid
treatment is different, if we look into it then
mostly there are surgeries like
appendix surgery,
angiography or therapy, eye surgery
like cataract
etc or radiotherapy or sinus
surgery, dialysis, even
if you have any bone fracture in it,
that too is covered in day treatment, so
friends it is very important to understand day care
because different companies
provide day care services in different markets and their terms and conditions are
also different, so if you have taken
any policy or if you are
planning to take any policy then you should
see what are the conditions of day care
because this surgery, in our
day today life, many
such services are available which are common,
so let us know
which companies are there,
see how much treatment is covered in it.  Yes,
some companies say that
I have 144 treatments and their list is
mentioned inside the policy document,
if you do any treatment outside this list then
it will
not be covered in day treatment, similarly
some companies say that we have a list of 170
diseases which we will cover, in this way
some companies say that we will
cover more than 400 treatments which can be
possible after seeing and some companies even
say that any treatment means
we will cover ward treatment, that any
treatment is such which can be done in day care as per the
advice of the doctor, then
we will cover it in day treatment,
but friends, it is
very important to understand that it is very
important to make an admission slip and distance loop here so that it does
not happen that you
go to the hospital for treatment and it is
considered in the audio player, but you do
not get the admission and discharge done there,
if you do this then you will not
get the claim, so it is very important to understand
that whenever you go for treatment then get the
admission and discharge
slip made in it  Secondly, the
best feature within this is that we
know that these are diseases that
we won't need immediately in an emergency.
Seasonal diseases are such that
we have pre-planned surgery, which we
know that if we need cataract surgery,
we have already made an
appointment with the doctor for the surgery. So
what we can do here is we
can get a little admission from the insurance company
because here the hospital already has the effect
that we need to get treatment in a hospital or
a day-care center right now.
If
that company has services there, then you can
go there and file a complete authorization.
Meaning that you have already obtained
a guarantee letter from the company that I will get
treatment for this surgery till this date, then
you will give me the cover. This is a kind of
pre-approval letter that all
insurance companies provide.
So let's learn a little about the different
types of conditions in different insurance companies. If you
look at the first column on the left, it is
a healthcare complaint of fraud from the IIT.  Helpline's
policy says that any such
treatment where forests and local
anesthesia has been given and
why the hospital is for 24 hours, hmm, that will be covered. There is a
strip prefix list of some diseases in this plan and
you should go and see it, there you will come to know
which
diseases are covered under ICC. If we
talk about maths here, this is Max Bupa's
pimples plan, its policy says that
here
they have written that Billi
DFID medical expenses included in short bursts and
day's treatment for the
following laser surgery, but they have put
a condition here that here the
hospitalization should be minimum more than two hours,
that whatever your
procedure is, it should be of at least 2 hours,
friends, like angiography,
dialysis, radiotherapy,
chemotherapy for cancer, so friends,
if here 2 hours means your admission
and discharge time is not there, then you will
not get the claim here, so if you have taken any
policy, then it is very
important for you to understand here.  It should not happen that you
go and then you do not get the claim later.
Similarly, if
you look at the stars here, then most of the companies
say that here we will cover
any treatment within 24 hours in
which general anesthesia has been given, that
is, any such surgery has been done in
which you have been
given one-third i.e. unconscious medicine
and after that you have been treated, then
we will cover it. Similarly, if
I talk about the ad, then here also it is
clearly written that medical
treatment is a surgical procedure undertaken
under general and local anesthesia. So
friends, I would just request you
that whenever you
go for treatment, then go to the hospital beforehand and
file your desired return so that you will
know a day before or before getting the treatment done whether the
procedure you are going to get done will be
covered in day cricket or
not. So, I hope that
your knowledge will increase from this video of mine and please, if
you like my video, then
definitely like and subscribe to my channel and share
this original video with your friends as well.  Share it
so that it
reaches more people who need treatment for these
and also those who are related to insurance so that they can
get the benefit of Awaaz Dhan.
Thank you very much for watching this video.